RG 079:016, Department of Environmental Protection: Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation
Connecticut State Library
Department of Environmental Protection natural resources and outdoor recreation records
1940-2006
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection
25.25 cubic feet
Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation records include: Law Enforcement; Deputy Commissioner; Parks and Recreation; Water and Related Resources.
RG079_016
Multiple
Historical Note
With the creation of the Department of Environmental Protection in 1971, the Preservation & Conservation Division was given the mission to protect, conserve and mangage the land, water and wildlife resources of the state.1 Now known as the Bureau of Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation, this part of the Dept. of Environmental Protection has always been based on species management (fisheries, wildlife, forestry) and land use (recreation, open space, natural areas, etc.)2
See also the.
Endnotes
1Press release, November 22, 1971, RG 079:001, Department of Ennvironmental Protection, Commissioner Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., Accession 2005-009, Organizational Evaluation, Box 6, Folder "First DEP Org Dan Lufkin Documents".
2Untitled and undated document, RG 079:001, Ennvironmental Protection, Commissioner Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., Accession 2005-009, Organizational Evaluation, Box 6, Folder "Historic Org Charts".
Scope and Content
Included are Law Enforcement arrest cards and correspondence, 1940-1987. The bulk of the arrest cards date from the predecessor Board of Fisheries and Game; Deputy Commissioner, 1975-2006; the Governor's Task Force Report on State Beaches and Shoreline Parks, 1975, from the Parks and Recreation Unit; and files from Joseph O. Elmer, 1966-1975. Elmer was a senior civil engineer in the Water and Related Resources Unit.
Arrangement
Series numbers have been assigned within RG 079 in its entirety and therefore the series described here are not numbered consecutively.
Series 2. Law Enforcement, 1940-1987
Accession: 1993-134, Arrest Cards, 1940-1978, 4 cubic feet
Accession: 1993-136 (part), Correspondence, 1973-1987, 0.75 cubic feet
Series 16. Deputy Commissioner, 1975-2006
Accession: 1995-062, Theodore Brampton (? - 1979), Dennis DeCarli (1979-1991), Thomas Dudchik (1991-1993), George Avitable (1993-1995), 1979-1995, 10 cubic feet
Accession: 2006-007, Susan C. Lavoie, 1995-1998, 8 cubic feet
Accesion: 2007-010, David K. Leff, 2000-2006, 1 cubic foot
Series 24. Parks and Recreation, 1975, Accession: 2003-017, 0.5 cubic feet
Series 27. Water and Related Resources, 1966-1975
Accession 1988-027 (part), Joseph O. Elmer, Senior Civil Engineer, 1966-1975, 1 cubic foot
Related Material
Additional Department of Environmental Protection records can be found in:
RG 079:001, Central Office
RG 079:004, Aerial photographs, see the.
RG 079:006, Air, Waste and Water
RG 079:018, Office of Indian Affairs
As well in these predecessor departments, boards, and commissions:
RG 079:003, Board of Fisheries and Game
RG 079:017, State Park and Forest Commission
RG 079:022, Forestry Department
RG 079:023, Water Resources Commission
RG 079:026, State Harbor Commissioners for New Haven Harbor
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection; Connecticut. Board of Fisheries and Game; Connecticut. Bureau of Natural Resources; Connecticut. Bureau of Outdoor Recreation
Persons:
Brampton, Theodore; DeCarli, Dennis; Dudchik, Thomas; Avitable, George; Lavoie, Susan C; Leff, David K
Subjects:
Aquatic parks and reserves -- Connecticut; Beaches -- Connecticut; Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Board of Fisheries and Game -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Bureau of Natural Resources -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Bureau of Outdoor Recreation -- Records and correspondence; Environmental protection -- Connecticut; Fisheries -- Connecticut; Game protection-- Connecticut; Game wardens-- Connecticut; Parks -- Public use -- Connecticut; Recreation areas -- Public use -- Connecticut; Wildlife conservation -- Connecticut; Wildlife management -- Connecticut; Water resources development -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Reports; Speeches
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 2. Law Enforcement, 1940-1987
  - Arrest Cards, 1940-1978; 1993-134
    Information cards documenting arrests for violations of hunting and fishing laws and regulations. Includes materials from the predecessor Board of Fisheries and Game.
    - 1940-1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950-1960 (Box 2)
    - 1961-1971 (Box 3)
    - A-C, 1972-1978 (Box 3)
    - D-Z, 1972-1978 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1987; 1993-136 (part)
    Part of this accession is correspondence from the Board of Fisheries and Game, the predecessor to the Law Enforcement Division, and is described in the finding aid for that Board.
    - Mimeograph copies (Box 2)
    - Correspondence All Districts, 1982 January - 1984 June (Box 2)
    - Corresopndence All Districts, 1983 October - 1985 January (Box 2)
    - Correspondence Eastern District, 1982 February - 1985 March (Box 2)
    - Arrest & Warnings, 1984 July - 1985 June (Box 2)
    - Arrest & Warnings, 1985 July - 1986 June (Box 2)
    - Western District Correspondence, 1982 March - 1985 January (Box 2)
    - All Districts, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Safari Wildlife Office of the year, 1973-1987 (Box 2)
- Series 16. Deputy Commissioner, 1975-2006
  - Theodore Brampton (? - 1979), Dennis DeCarli (1979-1991), Thomas Dudchik (1991-1993), George Avitable (1993-1995), 1979-1995; 1995-062
    - Correspondence, 1979-1995 (Box 1)
      - AA - GD (Box 1)
      - GE - McK (Box 2)
      - McL - ST (Box 3)
      - SU - Z (Box 4)
    - Deputy Commissioner DeCarli and his directors files, 1979-1990 (Box 4)
    - Deputy Commissioner Avitable staff files, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
      - Babcock (Box 4)
      - Buyak (Box 4)
      - Cantele (Box 4)
      - Clifford (Box 4)
      - Couch (Box 4)
      - Herig (Box 4)
      - Jones (Box 4)
      - Spencer (Box 4)
      - Whitham (Box 4)
      - George Avitabile (Box 4)
      - Budget Memo’s/Cheryl Brandt (Box 4)
      - John Spencer (Box 4)
      - Chuck Phillips (Box 4)
    - Property Acquisition files, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
      - Arrigoni Property (Box 4)
      - Belding Property/Mgmt Area (Box 4)
      - Hopyard-Danikow Property (Box 4)
      - Lake Williams (Box 4)
      - Meshomasic St. Forest/Rattlesnakes (Box 4)
      - Land Trade/Town of Lyme/Hartman Park/Nehantic St. Forest (Box 4)
      - Savin Property/Colchester/Lebanon, CT (Box 4)
      - Pachaug Pond/Welcome Burdick Property (Box 4)
    - DEP Intradepartmental Correspondence, 1975-1995 (Box 5)
      - Administration (Box 5)
      - Affirmative Action (Box 5)
      - Attorney General (Box 5)
      - Boating Education (Box 5)
      - Boating Access/Navigation Safety (Box 5)
      - Conservation Field Support (Box 5)
      - Commissioner (Box 5)
      - Data Processing (Box 5)
      - Eastern District (Box 5)
      - Field Services/T. Linkkila (Box 5)
      - Financial Services (Box 5)
      - Fisheries (Box 5)
      - Forestry (Box 5)
      - Information & education (Box 5)
      - Indian Affairs (Box 5)
      - Law enforcement (Box 5)
      - Land Acquisition (Box 5)
      - Division of Property Acquisition (Box 5)
      - Land Acquisition (Box 5)
      - Grants in Aid (Box 5)
      - Land Acquisition & Management (Box 5)
      - Management Analysis (Box 5)
      - Natural Resources (Box 5)
      - Parks (Box 5)
      - Personnel (Box 5)
      - Purchasing & Central Services (Box 5)
      - Richard Cassada Telecommunications (Box 5)
      - Wild Life (Box 5)
      - Western District (Box 5)
      - Bureau of Environmental Services (Box 5)
      - Coastal Resources Mgmt/Rachel Towbin (Box 5)
      - Planning Group (Box 5)
      - Strategic Planning (Box 5)
      - Strategic Planning 2 (Box 5)
      - Water Resources (Box 5)
    - Interderpartment Correspondence, 1977-1995 (Box 6)
      - Memorandum, States (Box 6)
      - Department of Corrections/Services (Box 6)
      - Department of Agriculture (Box 6)
      - Department of Economic Development (Box 6)
      - Department of Motor Vehicles (Box 6)
      - Office of Policy & Management (Box 6)
      - Department of Public Works (Box 6)
      - DAS Reginald Smith (Box 6)
      - Bureau of Purchases-John Otterbein (Box 6)
      - Department of Safety-Div. Of St. Bl. (Box 6)
      - Water Compliance (Box 6)
      - Cam Program-Coastal Area Mgmt. (Box 6)
    - Constituent letters, 1993-1995; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Subject files, 1980-1995 (Box 6)
      - ADA Compliance (Box 6)
      - Algonquin Gas Transmission (Box 6)
      - American Disabilities Act (Box 6)
      - DEP Annual Report (Box 6)
      - Aquatic Resource Education (Box 6)
      - Army Corps of Engineers (Box 6)
      - Arrow Device (Box 6)
      - ATV’S (Box 6)
      - Atlantic Waterfowl Council (Box 6)
      - Atlantic Waterfowl Council, 1990 July 25-29 (Box 6)
      - Architectural Design Contest (Box 6)
      - Bartlett Arboretum (Box 6)
      - Bluff Point (Box 6)
      - Beardsley Zoo (Box 6)
      - Beacon Hill/Stewardship Acct. (Box 6)
      - Boating Certificate Program (Box 6)
      - Boating Safety (Box 6)
      - Boating Advisory Council (Box 7)
      - Boating Safety (Box 7)
      - Boat Speed/Noise Level (Box 7)
      - Budget Options (Box 7)
      - Bond Commissioner Mtg. (Box 7)
      - Budget Options (Box 7)
      - Kathryn Burton (Box 7)
      - Bureau Plans (Box 7)
      - Cenacle Property (Box 7)
      - Citizen’s Advisory Council (Box 7)
      - Claims Commissioner (Box 7)
      - Clinton Land Conservation Trust/Proposed (Box 7)
      - Trail System (Box 7)
      - Coastal Waterfowl Hunting (Box 7)
      - Commissioner’s Meeting (Box 7)
      - Complaint’s Hunter Harassment (Box 7)
      - Collect System DEP Communications/R. (Box 7)
      - Cassada (Box 7)
      - Congressional Priorities (Box 7)
      - Contingency Plan-Essential Services (Box 7)
      - Connecticut Horse Council (Box 7)
      - Conservation Officers (use of vehicles) (Box 7)
      - Cream Hill School (Box 7)
      - Connecticut Forest & Park Assoc. (Box 7)
      - Great Connecticut River Raft Race (Box 7)
      - Great Connecticut River Raft Race 2 (Box 7)
      - Connecticut River Raft Race (Box 7)
      - Connecticut Marine Trades Assoc. (CMTA) (Box 7)
      - Connecticut State Muzzloader Association (Box 7)
      - CT. State Park Urban Symposium, 1994 (Box 7)
      - Connecticut Water Co. Land Trade Proposal (Box 7)
      - Council of Environmental Quality (Box 7)
      - Deer Management Study (Box 7)
      - DEP Environmental Magazine (Box 7)
      - DEP Employee Awards (Box 7)
      - Deputy Commissioner’s Staff Mtg. (Box 7)
      - Distinguished Service Award (Box 7)
      - Early Retirement Impact (Box 7)
      - Environment, 2000 (Box 7)
      - Employee Housing (Box 7)
      - Endangered Species Advisory Bill (Box 7)
      - State Ethics Commission (Box 7)
      - Fairfield League of Sportsmen’s Club (Box 7)
      - Federal Aid Correspondence (Box 7)
      - Firearms Permit Examines (Box 7)
      - Fishing Dock-Camp Harkness (Box 7)
      - Freedom of Information Act (Box 7)
      - Flaherty Field Trial Area (Box 7)
      - Garaging of State Motor Vehicles (Box 7)
      - Ft Hale Pier-New Haven (Box 7)
      - Gay City Hunting Complaints (Box 7)
      - Goettlick Closure Cockaponsett S.F. (Box 7)
      - Gelco Lease Proposal (Box 7)
      - Glastonbury Shooting Range (Box 7)
      - Grass Carp (Box 7)
      - Great hill Pond (Box 7)
      - Hammonasset Natural Area Preserve (Box 7)
      - Heritage Park (Box 7)
      - Harkness Memorial (Box 7)
      - Harbor Masters (Box 7)
      - High Rock Rand/Naugatuck State Forest (Box 7)
      - Horse Council (Box 8)
      - Hunter Education-NRA Award (Box 8)
      - Hunting/Fishing License Structure (Box 8)
      - Hunter Accident/Killing, 1992 November (Box 8)
      - Hunter Harassment Bill (Box 8)
      - Int’l Assoc. Of Fish & Wildlife Agencies (Box 8)
      - Illegal Animals (Box 8)
      - Int’l Atl. Salmon Foundation (Box 8)
      - Iroquois Gas Pipe Line (Box 8)
      - Kings Island/Wildlife Mgmt Area/Nu & (Box 8)
      - DEP (Box 8)
      - Kitchel Wildlife Sanctuary (Box 8)
      - Land Acquisition Priorities (Box 8)
      - Lake of Isles/ Ledyard (Box 8)
      - Lake Williams (Box 8)
      - Lake Terramuggs (Box 8)
      - Lake Waramaug (Box 8)
      - Larking Bridle trail (Box 8)
      - Lattin’s Cove (Box 8)
      - Law Enforcement in State Parks, 1994 (Box 8)
      - Legislative Proposals, 1994 (Box 8)
      - Liability Decisions (Box 8)
      - License Fee Increases (Box 8)
      - Long Island Sound Program (Box 8)
      - Low-Level Radioactive Waste (Box 8)
      - License Review (Box 8)
      - Management Advisory Council (Box 8)
      - Mandates (Box 8)
      - Mattatuck State Forest-Historical (Box 8)
      - Mattatuck Shooting Range (Box 8)
      - Mansfield Training Center/Nathan Hale (Box 8)
      - Mark Twain Memorial (Box 8)
      - Milford Point (Box 8)
      - Migratory Waterfowl Stamp (Box 8)
      - Mohawk Mountain (Box 8)
      - Mohegan Indians (Box 8)
      - Multiple Use Resource Mgmt. Plan (Box 8)
      - Municipalities (Box 8)
      - Munster Property/Valley RR (Box 8)
      - Mute Swan Policy (Box 8)
      - Natural Area Preserves Adv. Committee (Box 8)
      - Natural Area Preserves (Box 9)
      - Natural Conservancy (Box 9)
      - Northeast Utilities (Box 9)
      - Northeast Fish & Wildlife Conf. (Box 9)
      - Northeast Assoc. Of F & W Agencies (Box 9)
      - OPM Funds/Program Initiatives (Box 9)
      - Outdoor Expo, 1991 (Box 9)
      - Outdoor Writer’s Conference, 1993 (Box 9)
      - Park Closings/Bans (Box 9)
      - Parks & Recreation (Box 9)
      - Penfield Reef (Box 9)
      - PPT (Box 9)
      - Permanent Recreational Rights Program (Box 9)
      - Pequonnock Valley Property (Box 9)
      - Permanent Easements (Box 9)
      - Plumb Hill Shooting Preserve (Box 9)
      - Post Farm/Hop River (Box 9)
      - Pow Wow (Box 9)
      - Prison Labor (Box 9)
      - Progressive Management (Box 9)
      - Project Wild & PLT (Box 9)
      - Public Service Announcement (Box 9)
      - Putnam Boat Launch (Box 9)
      - Recreation & Natural Heritage Trust (Box 9)
      - Red Cedar Lake (Box 9)
      - DEP-Regulations (Box 9)
      - Riverside Boat Launch-Hartford (Box 9)
      - Rockfall Foundation (Box 9)
      - Rocky Neck (Box 9)
      - Salmon River Siltation/Ice (Box 9)
      - Seafarms (Box 9)
      - Scenic Road Adv. Committee (Box 9)
      - Scorp National Park Serv. (Box 9)
      - Septage Lagoons (Box 9)
      - AAC Safe Boating Certificates (Box 9)
      - Seasonal Position/Policy (Box 9)
      - Shakespeare Theater (Box 9)
      - Shakespeare Task Force (Box 9)
      - Shooting Ranges-Northeast (Box 10)
      - Shepaug Eagle Observation Program (Box 10)
      - Shetucket River/Natural Heritage Corner (Box 10)
      - Silver Sands-Development Project (Box 10)
      - Soundview (Box 10)
      - Manuel Soares/Yellowtail Founder Artist (Box 10)
      - Summer Employment (Box 10)
      - State-owned Housing (Box 10)
      - State Park System Fee Structure (Box 10)
      - State Park Closures April, 89 (Box 10)
      - State Police-Tower Site (Box 10)
      - State Motor Vehicle (garaging assignments) (Box 10)
      - Steel jaw Traps (Box 10)
      - Stillwater Pond (Box 10)
      - Stone Ranch Control Deer Hunt (Box 10)
      - Strategic Plans (Box 10)
      - Sunday Hunting (Box 10)
      - Sunnybrook Parks Clean-up (Box 10)
      - Swans/Egg Shaking Proposal, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Thomas Commission Study (Box 10)
      - Transition Team (Box 10)
      - Estate of Norma Terris/Willed to DEP (Box 10)
      - U.S. Dept. Of Interior/Fish & Wildlife’ (Box 10)
      - Urban Forestry Program (Box 10)
      - U.S. Navy DEP Parking Permit (Box 10)
      - US Surgical (Box 10)
      - Volunt. Cons. Officer Assistance Program (Box 10)
      - Waterman Property (Box 10)
      - Weir Farm (Box 10)
      - Westport Shooting Incident 150/500 Regs (Box 10)
      - West Rock Ridge State Park (Box 10)
      - Whalebone Cove Nature Conservancy (Box 10)
      - Wildlife Society (Box 10)
      - Wildlife Mgt. Economic Data (Box 10)
      - Wildlife Administrators (Box 10)
      - Wooster Mtn. (Box 10)
      - Wooster Mtn. (Box 10)
      - White Memorial Foundation (Box 10)
  - Susan C. Lavoie, 1995-1998; 2006-007
    - Subject Files
      - Accident-Boating-Housatonic (Box 1)
      - Accident-Boating-Nozko (Box 1)
      - Accident-Hunting-Paugussett (Box 1)
      - ADA Projects (Box 1)
      - Affirmative Action (Box 1)
      - Agency Information Technology Plan (AITP) (Box 1)
      - Agency Support Services (Box 1)
      - Alcohol Ban (Box 1)
      - American Legion State Forest (Box 1)
      - Annual International Awards For Excellence on The Waterfront (Box 1)
      - Annual Northeast and Wildlife Conference (Box 1)
      - Atlantic States Marine Fisheries CommissionAtlantic Whales (Box 1)
      - Audit Report (Box 1)
      - Automated Sports Licensing System (Box 1)
      - Babcock Pond Wildlife (Box 1)
      - Baldwin Bridge Boat Launch (Box 1)
      - Bass (Box 1)
      - Beaver Brook (Box 1)
      - Beardsley Park (Box 1)
      - Bethany Training Center (Box 1)
      - Bicycle Trails (Box 1)
      - Big "E" (Box 1)
      - Bigelow Hollow State Park (Box 1)
      - Bikeathon (Box 1)
      - Blackfish (Box 1)
      - Black Rock State Park (Box 1)
      - Blake-Coleman Property (Box 1)
      - Blithewold (Box 1)
      - Bluff Point (Box 1)
      - Boating Advisory Councel (Box 1)
      - Boating Fund Budget (Box 1)
      - Boating (Box 1)
      - Boat Launches (Box 1)
      - Boating Regulations (Box 1)
      - Bomster, Bill and Joe (Box 1)
      - Bond Agenda, 1996 (Box 1)
      - Bond Agenda, 1997 (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Outdoor Recreation-Budget (Box 1)
      - Bridge Repair Program (Box 1)
      - Briggs Property (Box 1)
      - Budget, FY 98, FY 99 (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Natural Resources (MISC) (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Natural Resources - Budget (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Natural Resources - Funding (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Natural Resources Survey (Box 1)
      - BOR Legislation (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Waste Management (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Water (Box 1)
      - Burlington Hatchery (Box 1)
      - Camp Rowland (Box 1)
      - Canada (Box 1)
      - Canal Line Trail (Box 1)
      - Candlewood lake (Box 1)
      - Canine Unit (Box 1)
      - Capital Equipment (Box 2)
      - Capital Projects (Box 2)
      - Capital Theatre (Box 2)
      - Career Day, 1997 (Box 2)
      - CBIA (Box 2)
      - CBIA - Summer Session Program (Box 2)
      - Chatfield Hollow State Park (Box 2)
      - Cities (Box 2)
      - Citizen's Advisory Council (Box 2)
      - Clark Kimberly, 1996 January 23 (Box 2)
      - Clean Vessel Act (Box 2)
      - Coastal Crant, 1997 (Box 2)
      - Coastal Signage (Box 2)
      - Coca Cola Sponsor (Box 2)
      - Cockaponset State Park (Box 2)
      - Commercial Fishing License Moratorium (Box 2)
      - Commissioner's Initiatives (Box 2)
      - Communication's Memos (Box 2)
      - Communications Press (Box 2)
      - Compo Cove Park Association (Box 2)
      - Computerized Toll Stations (Box 2)
      - Comstock Bridge (Box 2)
      - Concessions - State Parks (Box 2)
      - CT Coastline Port Authority (Box 2)
      - CT Humanities Council (Box 2)
      - CT Marine Trades Association (Box 2)
      - Conservation Officer Volunteer Program (Box 2)
      - CT Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 2)
      - CT Antique Machinery (Box 2)
      - CT Certified Environmental Program (Box 2)
      - CT Conference of Municipalities (CCM) (Box 2)
      - CT Congressional Districts (Box 2)
      - CT Conservation Officers Association (Box 2)
      - CT Economic Research Center (CERC) (Box 2)
      - CT Forest and Park Association, Inc. (Box 2)
      - CT Forest Legacy Program (Box 2)
      - Connecticut Horse Council Inc. (Box 2)
      - Connecticut Intrastate Fire Crew (Box 2)
      - CT Recreation and Parks Association (Box 2)
      - Connecticut Releaf Festival (Box 2)
      - CT/RI Coastal Flyfishers (Box 2)
      - CT River (Box 2)
      - CT Seafood Council (Box 2)
      - CT Tourism Council (Box 2)
      - CT Trail Advisory Board (Box 2)
      - CT Trails Day, 1996 June 1 (Box 2)
      - CT Trails Day, 1997 (Box 2)
      - CT Trust for Historic Preservation (Box 2)
      - Council on Environmental Quality (Box 2)
      - Coventry Lake (Box 2)
      - Customer Service Awards (Box 2)
      - Day Pond State Park (Box 2)
      - Department of Administrative Services (Box 2)
      - Department of Consumer Protection (Box 2)
      - Department of Corrections Land (Box 2)
      - Department of Economic and Community Development (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection- Accomplishments, 1995 (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection- Agency Budget (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection - Articles (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection - Firefighters (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection - Guide (Box 2)
      - Department of Environmental Protection - Leases (Box 2)
      - DEP- Program / Project Prioritization (Box 2)
      - DEP- Protection Properties (Box 2)
      - DEP- 25th Anniversary (Box 2)
      - DEP- Washington Office (Box 2)
      - Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services (Box 2)
      - Department of Public Safety (Box 2)
      - Department of Public Work-Leasing (Box 2)
      - Department of Transportation (Box 2)
      - Dinosaur State Park (Box 3)
      - Dinosaur State Park - Reopening, 1996 June 30 (Box 3)
      - Directives (Box 3)
      - Distinquish Service Awards (Box 3)
      - Division of Forestry (Box 3)
      - Donation Account (Box 3)
      - Drawdowns (Box 3)
      - Duck Stamp Program (Box 3)
      - Education Plan-Goodwin, Kellogg and Session Woods (Box 3)
      - Emergency Dispatch Center (Box 3)
      - Employment Applications (Box 3)
      - Endangered Species (Box 3)
      - Environment Committee (Box 3)
      - William Phelps Eno Mansion (Box 3)
      - Uno mansion (Box 3)
      - Environment, 2000 (Box 3)
      - EPA (Box 3)
      - ERI/DEP Research Council (Box 3)
      - Events (Box 3)
      - Falconry (Box 3)
      - Farmland Preservation (Box 3)
      - Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Properties FDIC (Box 3)
      - Field Services (Box 3)
      - 5th Alabama Battalion Field Music (Box 3)
      - Financial and Support Services (Box 3)
      - Firefighters-Connecticut (Box 3)
      - Fisheries (Box 3)
      - Fisheries Advisory Council (Box 3)
      - Fisheries Regulations (Box 3)
      - Fishing Easement Bond Accounts (Box 3)
      - Fishing Licenses (Box 3)
      - Flaherty Field (Box 3)
      - Fluke (Box 3)
      - Fodor Farm (Box 3)
      - Forestry-Pauchaug State Nursery (Box 3)
      - Forestry Regulations (Box 3)
      - FOI Requests (Box 3)
      - Fort Griswold (Box 3)
      - Fort Nathan Hale (Box 3)
      - Fort Shantok (Box 3)
      - Fort Trumbull-New London (Box 3)
      - Franklin House-Wildlife Management Area (Box 4)
      - Friends of CT State Parks (Box 4)
      - Friends of CT. State Parks Reception (Box 4)
      - Garbage (Box 4)
      - General Fund (Box 4)
      - Gillette Castle (Box 4)
      - Gillette Castle Repairs (Box 4)
      - Gillette Castle Christmas Party (Box 4)
      - Goodwin Conservation Center (Box 4)
      - Goshen Cove (Box 4)
      - Governor's Briefing Reports (Box 4)
      - Governor's Residence (Box 4)